Flying has revolutionised the way we navigate the world.
飞行彻底改变了我们在世界范围内穿行的方式。
It's often the quickest and most convenient way to travel long distances.
它通常是长途旅行中最快捷、最方便的方式。
But there's a catch – it's one of the most carbon-intensive activities the average person is likely to do.
但这里有一个问题——这是普通人可能做的最碳密集的活动之一。
In 2018, a small group of celebrities in Sweden led the 'flygskam' movement, meaning 'flight shame' in English, to encourage people to give up flying.
2018年，瑞典的一小群名人发起了"flygskam"运动，英文意为"飞行耻辱"，以鼓励人们放弃乘坐飞机。
But, for people who need or love to travel, what can we offer as green alternatives?
但是，对于需要或热爱旅行的人来说，我们能提供哪些绿色替代方案呢？
For medium to long-distance travel, it seems trains are our best bet.
对于中长途旅行来说，火车似乎是我们最好的选择。
Using a train instead of a domestic flight reduces emissions by 86%, according to the 2023 article 'Which form of transport has the smallest carbon footprint?'.
根据2023年文章《哪种交通方式的碳足迹最小？》，使用火车代替国内航班可减少86%的排放量。
A downside is that trains can be more expensive than flying with low-cost airlines.
一个缺点是火车可能比乘坐廉价航空更贵。
Another is that it might take hours longer to reach your destination, and most people don't want to spend a large part of their trip travelling from A to B.
另一个缺点是到达目的地可能需要多花几个小时，而大多数人不愿意把旅途的大部分时间花在路上。
That's where sleeper trains come in.
这时候可以选择卧铺列车。
European rail networks are expanding, which means passengers can travel while sleeping and wake up in a new city or country!
欧洲的铁路网络正在扩张，这意味着乘客可以在睡觉时旅行，醒来时便到达一个新的城市或国家！
For shorter distances, many would be willing to swap cars for bicycles, but few would consider cycling internationally.
对于较短距离的旅行，许多人愿意用自行车代替汽车，但很少有人会考虑跨国骑行。
Among those few, Matilda Welin.
马蒂尔达·韦林就是少数人之一。
It took her 17 days to cycle from London to Sweden.
她从伦敦骑车到瑞典花了17天。
Sadly, she concluded that her trip neither benefitted the planet nor saved her money.
遗憾的是，她得出结论说，她的旅行既没有让地球受益，也没有为她省钱。
But, it did change her perspective.
但是，这确实改变了她的视角。
She says "As I pedalled, I felt I was experiencing the true distance of the journey I take so casually and so often with a plane."
她说："当我蹬着踏板时，我感到我正在体验我经常漫不经心地乘坐飞机时所走旅程的真实距离。"
She describes how the world around her changed slowly; the languages, the architecture, the landscapes – something she wouldn't have appreciated on a flight.
她描述了她周围的世界如何缓慢变化：语言、建筑、风景——这些都是她在飞行中无法欣赏到的。
Unfortunately for the planet, air travel remains a popular option – around 100,000 planes take off globally per day.
对地球来说不幸的是，航空旅行仍然是一个受欢迎的选择——全球每天约有10万架飞机起飞。
But, further investment in rail infrastructure and subsidising ticket fares could help get more people on trains than planes.
但是，对铁路基础设施的进一步投资以及补贴票价，可能有助于让更多人选择火车而不是飞机。